Colby L. Sawyer



835 NC Hwy 343 South, Camden, NC 27921

P:(252)-333-4057

colbysawyer37@outlook.com

Objective:

A diligent professional with proven experience in software development and management demonstrated by years of work in the corporate and academic space. A published academic who has become proficient in time management, team communication, customer experience, change management, hard work and fast learning. Experienced in writing and maintaining software from inception to realization.

Education:

3.0/4.0 GPA

Bachelor of Science - <u>Computer Science</u> w/Minor - <u>General Business Administration</u> East Carolina University Greenville, NC Fall 2017- Spring 2021

Associate of Science- General Education

College of the Albemarle Elizabeth City, NC 2016-2017 3.8/4.0 GPA

Skills:

- Technology proficient (Software, Hardware, Bash/Shell, Citrix Workspace, VMware)
- Programming Language proficient (Python, Java, C+, CSS/HTML5/SAS, JavaScript, Kotlin, Swift)
- Database Creation and Management Experience (SQL, SQLite, MS Access)
- o IoT/Virtualization Experience (Balena, Docker, Kubernetes, Splunk)
- Operating System proficient (Windows, Mac, Linux, Raspbian, BalenaOS)
- o Microsoft Office proficient (Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Outlook)

Work Experience:

Application Support & Development Internship

8 Week Program, - First Citizens Bank - Raleigh, NC

- Determined software requirements for current banking needs
- Communicated requirements to various organizations within the bank
- Prepared timeline for development of various new software tools
- O Determined plans for the implementation of new software tools as well as facilitating change. (change management)

<u>Summer 2020</u>

- Explored various Diversity and Inclusion initiatives
- Maintained current bank systems by providing outlet for correction of user-based exceptions
- Provided support for users of bank systems while also initiating clear follow-up communications to verify the success of support.

Academic Research - Multidisciplinary(ITCS/CS)

Dr. Ciprian Popoviciu - East Carolina University - Greenville, NC

- Designed, with several other students, a collection of Raspberry PI units mounted to Cisco WebEx technology to monitor network connectivity issues in the hopes of preventing/mitigating downtime.
- Designed, implemented and managed teams website and web-based interfaces to provide a dashboard for user accessibility
- Handled set-up of various physical and virtual labs.
- O Utilized SAS, Linux, Balena, Raspbian, IPERF, Cisco AnyConnect software
- O Utilized various open-source technologies, such as but not limited to, Docker, Phoronix Test Suite, BalenaOS

https://pi-pirates-ecu.github.io/PI-Pirates-Site/

Freelance Software Developer (Mobile)

Greenville, NC

- Communicated with customers regarding application features and timeline.
- Created development and iteration plan for logic/coding procedure
- Documented procedures for further development of product

January 2020 – Current

August 2019 – Current

- Managed **debugging** process, as well as, including plans for further iterations.
- Delivered product based on communicated timelines
- Maintained communication with customers to verify satisfaction

10-12 Week Program, – **Dominion Energy** - Elizabeth City, NC

- Determined facility design for material, time and cost estimates for the construction and maintenance of residential electrical constructions; as well as relocation of distribution facilities for customers.
- Maintained communication with customers to provide service in a time efficient manner
- Inspected work request job sites, determine metering requirements and prepare sketches of property and service agreements.
- Prepared joint use notification CATV permits, underground agreements, revenue calculations, etc.
- Obtained right-of-way and easement agreements and highway/railroad permits.
- Assisted in service restoration in the field during outages.

Customer Service & Main Office Assistant

January 2018 – January 2020

- Campus Recreation and Wellness Center East Carolina University Greenville, NC
 - Communicated with customers in person and via telephone and direct them to appropriate areas.
 Permitting access to the facility.
 - Used critical thinking skills to handle situations or conflicts that arise and communicate with other staff to resolve any issues.
 - Demonstrated knowledge of CRW programs & services including but not limited to: membership options/prices, CRW facilities/procedures, program areas, and professional staff area of responsibilities.
- Handled various payment methods for guest passes, late/lost fees, memberships, personal training sessions, aquatics activities, safety class registrations and lock sales throughout the day. Practice integrity while balancing the drawer at the beginning and end of shift.
- Worked weekends and holidays (even when classes are not in session) on a rotating basis.
- o Properly document lost and found items.

Publications:

Sawyer, Colby Lee. 2020. <u>Deploying a Network Management Overlay for Education Video Conferencing Services</u>. 2020 ASEE Virtual Annual Conference. https://www.asee.org/public/conferences/172/papers/29604/view

Sawyer, Colby Lee. 2020. <u>A Multidisciplinary Project: Deploying Edge Computing to Augment Endpoint Functionality</u>. 2020 ASEE Virtual Annual Conference. https://www.asee.org/public/conferences/172/papers/29638/view

Languages- English-Fluent, Spanish- Competent, ASL- Competent